Mirza Abdul Awal

10331 NW 12th Place Plantation, FL- 33322 1(954) 513-5171 awal.mirza2016@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Visual Design Skills
- User Interface Design
- Adaptability with new Tools
- Database Management
- Front End Programming
- Back End Programming

LANGUAGES

- Core Java
- Java Script

TOOLS

- VS Code
- Bracket
- Bootstrap CSS Framework
- Bulma CSS framework
- Foundation CSS Framework
- Node.is
- Handlebars
- Sequelize
- Inquirer
- Express
- No SQL
- PWA
- React

OBJECTIVE

An enthusiastic, devoted and proficient candidate having experience in the field of Quality Assurance (QA) and software development enriched with diverse expertise in Automation, and web design and development, with the capability of working in complex, fast paced and project-based environment. I am highly interested in building my career as a leading Software Development Professional in diverse domain of this industry.

PROFILE SUMMERY

Over 5 years of experience as automation QA and over 6 months of experience as software Development with the ability of using different tools that includes Selenium web driver, Bracket and VS Code. I have deeper understanding in Software Development Life Cycle following Agile and Waterfall methodology.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Student - Full Stack Developer U-Miami Boot Camp June 2021 - November 2021

QA Analyst ARC-One Solutions January 2020 - June 2021

- Performs quality control and quality assurance testing of applications using a set of testing tools, testing framework, processes and methodologies.
- Makes recommendations based on assessed risks to quality by applying various verification and validation techniques in coordination with the Developers, QA, and Managers.
- Provides feedback on the production readiness of the software being tested, allowing management to make a well-informed decision regarding the release of software into production.
- Analyzing Business Requirements for each process, writing Test Cases based on those requirements, generating and executing Test Runs using Helix, and logging the status of each of these assigned tasks into linked Jira board.
- Manages and executes testing for all test cases including integration, certification, user acceptance, system, regression, and load tests.
- Monitors, measures, and reports metrics based on the results of all tests.
- Conducts tests on computer software programs to make sure the programs perform properly and are easy to use; completes tests to determine weaknesses in software code and recommends program improvements or corrections to programmers.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Royal Roads University, BC, Canada Master's in Business Administration (Major in HRM) January 2007 to December 2008

National University, Gazipur, Bangladesh Masters in Defense Study January 2001 to December 2002

Chittagong University, Chittagong, Bangladesh Bachelor of Science June 1986 to June 1988